Language builds our world.
语言造就了我们的世界。
Our ideas make us who we are.
我们的想法塑造了我们。
And speakers who have figured out how to spread their ideas into others’ minds
那些能将自己的想法 传递给别人的演讲者
have the power to make an incredible impact.
有能力产生不可估量的影响。
Now ask yourself: do you have ideas that deserve a wider audience?
现在问问自己：你有值得 传递给更多听众的想法吗？
That can be a difficult question to answer.
这可以是 一个很难回答的问题。
Many people don't realize just how many valuable ideas they have.
许多人并没有意识到 他们有多少天才的想法。
You are the only you that's existed in all of human history.
你在人类历史上 是独一无二的存在。
Your experiences are yours and yours alone.
你的经历是你的， 而且只有你经历过。
Some of those experiences have taught you things
肯定有一些经历教会了你
that are absolutely worth sharing with an audience.
一些绝对值得被分享的东西。
You just have to figure out which experiences those are.
你只需要弄清楚哪一部分值得即可。
You may feel that you haven't done anything exciting enough
你可能会觉得自己没有 做任何足够刺激的事情
to give a talk about.
值得来发表演讲。
Maybe you tell yourself, “I’m not very creative” or, “I’m not very smart.”
也许你会告诉自己，“我不是很有创造力”， 或者，“我不是很聪明”。
Maybe you can't think of anything you feel passionate about right now.
也许你现在想不出 任何你感兴趣的东西。
Well, that's a tricky place to start.
好吧，开头看上去很难。
But you don’t need to worry.
但是你不必担心。
Because, the truth is, everyone has a great talk idea inside of them.
因为事实上每个人 都有很棒的想法值得分享。
Sometimes it just takes a little digging to find it.
有时只需要一点努力就能找到它。
One reason you may not recognize your great ideas
你没意识到这个好主意的原因
is that you have always been you.
可能是你太熟悉自己了。
You only see yourself from the inside.
你只从自己的角度看自己。
You may not notice the things that other people find remarkable about you.
你可能不会注意到 其他人眼中你的非凡之处。
That’s why one good way to uncover your talk-worthy ideas
这就是为什么和最了解你的人沟通
is to have conversations with the people who know you best.
是一个发现你亮点的绝佳方式。
They might be able to see things about you
他们也许能够看到你外在的
that you aren’t able to see about yourself—
你看不到的那些——
things that would be worth sharing with an audience.
值得与观众分享的东西。
There is one thing you have that no one else in the world has,
有一样东西是全世界 只有你一个人拥有的
and that is your experience.
那就是你的经验。
So another way to uncover your great ideas
因此，发现好主意的另一种方法
is to ask yourself questions about your life.
是自问自答一些有关生活的问题。
What was the last thing you were really excited by? Or angered by?
最后一件让你兴奋 或者生气的事情是什么？
What are some of the things that bring you joy?
什么东西能带给你快乐？
What annoys you?
什么东西让你烦恼？
What's something you're proud of?
你最引以为豪的是什么？
Is there something you know a lot about?
有什么事物你很了解？
A subject you could talk about for hours?
一个你可以谈上几个小时的话题？
Is there anything your community could teach other communities?
你所在的社群有什么 能分享给其他社群的？
What's a change you would like to see in the world?
你期待世界之后会发生 什么改变？
If you could wave a magic wand,
如果你有一次施展魔法的能力，
what's the one idea you'd most love to spread to other people's minds?
你最想传达给别人的信息是什么？
Spend some time walking around open to the possibility
花点时间想想这些， 打开思路
that some part of your unique journey could be interesting and helpful
相信你的一些独特经历 令观众
for an audience to learn about.
兴味盎然、受益匪浅。
Many wonderful talks are based on a personal story
许多精彩的演讲都是 根据个人故事
and a simple lesson the speaker took away from it.
和从中吸取的经验教训改编的。
Your idea could even be a question you're curious about.
你的想法甚至可以是你好奇的问题。
The search for an answer to your question could be the basis for your talk.
同样，寻找问题答案的过程 也可以作为你演讲的基础。
What are the issues that matter most to you?
对你来说最重要的问题是什么？
What are the riddles that people don't yet have good answers for?
人类还有哪些未解之谜？
If you have a subject you’d like to talk about,
如果你想谈论一个话题，
but aren't sure you really know enough yet,
但还不确定自己是否足够了解，
why not use your public speaking opportunity as a way to find out more?
为什么不利用你公开演讲的机会 来了解更多呢？
In other words, you don’t need to have the perfect knowledge
换句话说，你现在不必完全了解
in your head today.
所有的相关知识。
You could use your talk as the reason to discover more
你可以用你的演讲作为媒介来进一步
about something that interests you.
了解你感兴趣的事物。
The only thing that truly matters in public speaking is not confidence,
在公开演讲中 唯一真正重要的不是自信、
stage presence, or smooth talking.
舞台表现力或者流利程度，
It's having something worth saying.
而是有值得一说的话题。